[Music]
do
good evening good day everybody welcome
to the ask a buddy show episode 115. i
hope you are all doing very well
let us see who all is there with us
today
this fine evening i can see purobinath
goblet fire crazy brain gunpot laksha
dungar singh johan clash with pushkar
abhishek
yogesh
akshita
please don't spam lankish
and alan krita and lots of other people
good evening good day all of you great
to be all back with you all
so as you know today we discuss
history geopolitics current affairs so
let's get into it with question number
one
and obviously the first question i will
take today is about mr shinzo abe the
great leader of japan who has been
assassinated
uh and there's a bunch of questions here
who could be behind the shooting china
u.s internal reasons
so rather says comment on the recent
assassination uh what are your thoughts
on his duty as leader of japan how were
the ties with india in japan during this
time
aditya speaks about koreans being happy
about the assassination
rahil uh says about the sorrowful
assassination
do you think the americans were
responsible the chinese were happy and
celebrated and so on so forth so yeah
so the question is about
the unfortunate terrible
assassination of the leader of japan the
greatest leader of japan in recent times
mr shinzo abe
so uh first of all let me just
well pay my tribute to the great man i
mean he was a japan's longest ever
serving prime minister he was young
japan's youngest ever post-war prime
minister uh which he became in 2006
and
yeah japan's greatest leader maybe in
the past century certainly after world
war
ii
and he had at least a decade of active
political life left in him
he was he looked reasonably he looked
perfectly healthy to me and he was
campaigning on behalf of uh some other
politician when this
assassination happened
and uh
uh he was a true patriot and nationalist
and he was a true friend of india i mean
i have i am i've been saying this for
the longest time that there are no
friends or enemies in geopolitics and
international affairs
but in the case of mr shinzo abe that's
not true he was indeed a friend of india
so it's a great loss for japan and it's
a great loss for the civilized world and
a great loss for india so
yeah if anybody from japan is is
watching we stand with you the people of
india and we we mourn your leader who
has been taken away too early right
so the question is what what is the deal
with the assassination of mr abe who is
behind the shooting so let's first talk
about what the facts are the facts are
that he was assassinated in the
day before
a couple of days ago
what we know is that the assassin was a
former member of the japanese
self-defense forces he served in the
navy for a for a short brief period of
time two three years maybe
and he used a homemade weapon a homemade
double-barreled shotgun kind of thing uh
to assassinate mr abe and there are
plenty of videos of the assassination
circulating on social media
if you
watch these videos it becomes very clear
that this is a monumental security lapse
mr abe was japan's tallest leader the
longest serving prime minister the most
consequential and important leader in
the past 70 80 years maybe 100 years
and the kind of security he had was was
terrible his security people looked
bemused when the first shot rang out
if you watch the video videos of the
assassination it's clear that the first
shot missed mr abe it missed the target
and the and they were at least two three
seconds before the second shot rang out
and the the security people
they they failed in their duty they they
i mean it's criminal negligence what
they did they could have stopped the
assassin they could have uh taken this
away to safety in those two or three
seconds every second counts when it's uh
it's so it's a great leader like mr abe
they failed in the duty and the second
shot
if you
i mean i would not recommend that people
who have a faint heart would watch this
but the second shot hit mr abe you can
see the collar being flicked back
on the right side the right collar
yeah so it hit him somewhere here i
don't think i mean
is that a fatal injury mr abe did not
collapse he did not crumple he he walked
down he was clearly in pain he clutched
his uh that part of his body and then
what happened happened and eventually he
was declared dead so this is what we
know and if you
i believe the
uh the assassin seems to have said that
uh
so he expressed some religious reasons
or something for the assassination which
uh well
they don't quite make any sense but
that's what it is so these are the facts
that we have two days after the
assassination obviously they will
interrogate the the individual the
assassin and the history will come out
whatever the story is
so that's what we know
now the question is about the
involvement of whether it is internal
reasons whether it is china behind this
whether it's in whether it's uh the us
behind it whether the koreans are behind
it so now if we want to discuss this
this enters the realm of the realm of
speculation let me first explain
the difference between facts and
conspiracy theories
facts means you
speak about the evidence that is
available at hand the hard evidence
the evidence that has been reported and
officially reported those are the facts
when you make claims when a person make
claims that are not backed by evidence
those are that's a conspiracy theory
now if you want to uh talk about whether
china is behind this or the koreans are
behind this or the u.s behind this we
have
absolutely no evidence of any of that
i may have a hunch
but do i have any data or facts that
back up my hunch not really
and therefore it is it is wrong to
speculate this would be just wild
speculation
it is possible that there could be an
external factor
mr abe certainly did have enemies
obviously a man like him such as such a
consequential leader will have enemies
somebody who wants to change
japan
and who's a nationalist and who wants to
take japan in a certain direction which
other countries won't like
certainly china would feel threatened by
that by what mr abe
for the by the vision that mr abe had
for japan right so what did mr abbey
want he wanted to remove article 9 of
the japanese constitution which outlaws
war as a means of settling international
disputes so this article of the japanese
constitution denies japan's right to
believe jeremy
right it says japan can never go to war
only diplomacy and other means never
ever war
and we know who wrote the japanese
constitution it was the americans who
wrote it in 1945 and the constitution
has never been changed after ever since
so mr abe sought a different kind of
role for japan he believed he and he was
right in believing that the the
post-world war two era was long gone and
the new international order need to be
needed to be created right
so he wanted that
but obviously that will cause pro
it will certainly go against the
interests of certain countries the
chinese won't like it the koreans who
have this long grudge against the
japanese and rightfully so because of
the actions in world war ii the the
koreans won't like it the south koreans
i mean the americans they wrote the
constitution they they occupy japan
there are more than 100
dominant uh there are more than 100
american military bases on japanese soil
more than 130 possibly
yeah so the americans won't like it so
obviously it will ruffle a lot of
feathers and it will many people will
will see that as a threat but do we have
any evidence that any of these countries
did that we have no evidence whatsoever
none whatsoever so uh so
i i am not in a position to answer the
question of whether the chinese are
behind it or the koreans are behind it
or the americans are behind we have no
evidence whatsoever in about this matter
right we know who could be threatened by
that but we have no evidence so so if i
were to start speculating speculating
about this then you would be right in
calling me a conspiracy theorist but i'm
not that so i will not speak about this
but let's talk about uh what uh the lady
asked sanatori uh
the ties with india and japan at the
time so yes it is during mr abe's time
that the relationship between india and
japan essentially blossomed right
so mr abe became prime minister for the
first time for a year or so in 2006.
and i believe he visited india for the
first time in 2007 when uh the upa
government was in power
and uh
at the time mr abe was already mulling
the thought of creating the
quadrilateral alliance between india
japan australia and the united states
because he recognized the fact that the
world order was changing the chinese
rise was already apparent and it needed
to be counter balanced so mr abe at that
time itself
uh wanted to create the quadrilateral
alliance but at the time the indian
government was busy appeasing china
in 2006 in 2007 the indian government
was busy appeasing china
so that did not happen but in 2007 when
mr abe first visited india he made it a
point to go and visit mr modi in gujarat
so he met mr modi and that's where the
relationship between these two leaders
started
and
they got along very well they were both
fierce patriots they both belonged that
their nations needed to rise
to the rightful places in history uh mr
abe saw india as a civilizational
brother essentially
they he saw india as part of the same
civilization which it clearly is they
spoke about this on many occasions about
the very ancient and close and strong
civilizational ties between india and
japan whether it is buddhism whether it
is shinto and or all of that so he was
very clear about this that india and
japan are civilizational partners and
brothers essentially
and uh
yeah so he was a very good friend
of mr modi that that friendship evolved
over time that became stronger and
for the longest time on twitter mr abe
followed only three people one was a
a japanese journalist one was his wife
mrs abe and the third was mr modi and he
was following mr modi on twitter before
mr since before mr modi became prime
minister and after 2014 when mr modi
became prime minister the relationship
between india and japan truly took off
right so uh
what happened is that uh
many agreements were signed between
india japan lots of close coordination
began the bullet train agreement right
the smart cities co collaboration a
significant amount of defense
cooperation especially on the naval
front the international solar alliance
and of course the quadrilateral alliance
which is a very big thing now so mr abe
the quadrilateral lines the quad is mr
abe's brain joint brainchild it is he
who is essentially the initiator of that
and of course mr abe did multiple
reforms within japan itself the national
security council is something that he
created in 2013 and it's taken off so
a truly consequential person a very good
friend of india he truly had warmth in
his heart for india he truly wanted to
partner with india and take the two
countries forward and you can see that
you know when a certain foreign leader
comes to your country you can see
whether they are being polite or whether
they truly feel it and believe it so
when for instance when mr xi jinping
comes to india you can see that he's
going through the motion since he's
being polite to his hosts and
whatever cultural program is that he
goes and admires the artwork and all
that that sort of thing but when it came
to mr abe when he visited varanasi for
the for the ganga you could see he
actually felt that he was not acting he
was not being polite he actually felt
that emotion right so
that's why i said that mr abe is one of
the rare people who i would say was a
genuine friend of india and therefore it
is a big loss for india that mr abe has
been assassinated it's a big loss
obviously for the people of japan and
for the for the civilized world i would
say
so uh that is what i can
about this matter i will not indulge in
empty speculation i obviously have
a hunch about who may be behind this but
i don't have any evidence to back it up
and therefore i shall keep quiet about
that
okay this is an old question
one year ago from akash bula
but uh considering the situation right
now maybe it's an appropriate time to
look at to to
take this up so the question is
do you think lee harvey oswald really
killed president john f kennedy of the
us
the former raw chief vikram sood in his
book claimed that he was assassinated by
the cia because he was trying to shake
hands with the soviets at the time he
was soft on the soviets what do you
think
and related to this what is the deep
state
okay so let's uh
mr kennedy was assassinated in 1963 1963
was a
strange year
it was a year in which two world leaders
were assassinated one was mr kennedy
and the other
was
prime minister lal badu shastra
these two these two assassinations
happened i mean
uh mr shastri obviously we don't know
whether he was assassinated or not but
he died under mysterious circumstances
and the uh
the death has never been fully explained
and uh
uh i have a i have a podcast with mr
anujar on this channel in which we he he
speaks about this he's the subject
matter expert he's written a book about
this so if that's what interests you you
can take a look at this podcast or read
his book
so the other major event was the
assassination of president john f
kennedy and the official report is that
he was killed by a lone gunman
uh lee harvey oswald who was himself
assassinated by by a guy called ruby i
think jack ruby john ruby something like
that a few days later so he was silenced
forever
lee harvey was told the assassin himself
was assassinated in film in in full
public view live on tv that's what
happened uh it's a very murky strange
case and the official uh
explanation of the assassination the
warren uh commission report is that
there was a lone gunman so let me just
show you what it looks like shall we
take a look at this the warren
commission the warrant commission report
let me share that so it's available in
the public domain
this is what it looks like you could
look it up and google it and find it
this is what the warren commission
report looks like the entire uh
report
is available in the public domain
including
the assassination the summary and
conclusions
there's even an autopsy report that's
available
if that's something that you would be
interested in the autopsy report and so
on
so this is the warren commission report
and that's the official version of what
happened what does it say it says that
president kennedy was assassinated by a
lone gunman who fired multiple shots
from behind
so the assassination happened in the
city of dallas the the president and his
wife and the governor of texas were in
an open
car
an open top car there was no covering it
was open and they were driving down down
the road and then these shots rang out
and
and this entire assassination was
captured on tape on film
it's called the zapruder film the
zapruder tape or whatever it's called
it's i'm sure it's available in the
public domain i suppose it's available
on youtube as well
fair warning it's not a pleasant thing
to see the president's head essentially
explodes
it's it's a very graphic tape so if you
get upset easily don't watch it
but
the official report says that there was
a lone gunman who shot the president
from behind from a building on the
whatever seventh eighth ninth floor
something like that from a significant
distance using a sniper rifle
multiple shots at least two bullets hit
the president according to the official
uh report
and the fatal shot was in the head from
behind that's what the official version
says till today
now if you
are
if you were to watch
the tape the actual film of the
assassination
then you see something totally different
you see
that the president's head
is is jerked backwards
very violently and it essentially
explodes there is this entire big spray
of brain matter that happens
so it's clear that the bullet came from
the front
a bullet is a very
it's a very uh energetic projectile it
imparts a massive amount of
kinetic energy to the target it's like
getting a massive punch in the face but
from a very little piece of metal and
that's why it destroys whatever it hits
and therefore when a bullet hits a human
being a body or whatever there's a
massive uh
whiplash in the opposite direction to
opposite to the place from where the
bullet came so you can see in the film
that the president's head
is jerked backwards and then and it
explodes at the same time
so it's clear the bullet the fatal
bullet was fired from the front not from
the back anybody can see this
even a five-year-old can understand
where the bullet came from and yet the
official version says that he was shot
from behind from from building
so it makes no sense and obviously this
has been discussed threadbare this is a
big deal in the u.s even today people
are fascinated with this uh
oliver stone one of in one of america's
most respected filmmakers
has
done a great deal of work in this he uh
he uh
released a movie in 1991 which was a
fictional movie jfk which was a movie
with actors it was acting and there was
this fictional character and all that
played by kevin costner other people as
well i believe uh the guy who played
dracula played the role of lee harvey
oswald yeah and and so on right so that
was a movie in which it is claimed that
this was a big cover-up it was
something done by the american deep
state itself
and then there is a
newer documentary by
oliver stone it's called jfk revisited i
believe it's from last year i think in
which he goes into more detail about
with with more of the research that he
has done over the years
and if you look at if you watch these
documentaries they make a very
compelling case that lee harvey oswald
was not behind this it was somebody else
but
well you talk about this they will call
you conspiracy theories so nowadays they
call oliver stone a conspiracy theorist
even though he has a lot of data to back
up his claims and it's clear from
watching the film of the
the tapes of the assassination that
he the the fatal shot did not come from
behind it came from the front
so it's clear that there is a cover up
from the part of the united states
government
so yeah so i would agree with mr vic i i
mean i have not read the book
the one that you're referring to the one
by mr vikram sood but he is a very well
respected person he was india's former
uh
head of the research and analysis wing
so if he says something we have to take
it very seriously so if if this is what
he claimed then one must take it
seriously yeah
and what is the deep state the deep
state is the unelected
well it is once again alleged to
exist see officially in the u.s you have
a president who is the head of the
nation who is the person who makes takes
all the decision decisions and who is
the so-called leader of the free world
whatever they call it right that's the
claim they make
the deep state is the pentagon the the
military industry complex the people who
are never elected or taken or removed
from power they are always there whoever
that was the whoever is the president it
doesn't matter these are the people who
actually
run the machinery of the governance and
of the of the government
essentially the pentagon and
the cia fbi all of that that's what is
called the deep state this is not a
conspiracy theory i mean there's plenty
written about this lots of books about
that
and so on so that is what is meant by
the deep state the unelected
machinery of governance in the u.s which
essentially dictates foreign policy
internal policy and things like that
so that is the answer to this question
in
unbrief reasonably brief
all right let's talk about what else is
happening in the world ishwara modi says
can you please give us a gist of what's
happening right now in sri lanka what
will be india's next step
even after we have provided so much aid
already
and the kinship says the last member of
the raja paksha family left sri lanka on
saturday what do you think about it and
how does it impact india
right so what's happening in sri lanka
sri lanka is in a big
big mess right so the rajapaksas who
have been ruling the country essentially
for the past 15 or so years maybe longer
they are the most powerful family
in politics in sri lankan politics it's
a dynasty it's like three brothers and
they're still the children and who else
i don't know
it's an external family that essentially
holds much of the was holding much of
the power in sri lanka
so they have now left they have escaped
from the country these videos came up on
social media of the rajapaksa's escaping
running essentially running with big
suitcases and
going on this sri lankan navy ship to
escape the country
and more footage has emerged on social
media of the presidential palace being
invaded by crowds of common citizens
protesters right and people
swimming in the presidential swimming
pool and
whatnot
so that's what's happened the sri lankan
go
the country is right now without a
government there is no leader
there may be a titular leader a leader
who is by title president or prime
minister or whatever but actually there
is no government in sri lanka now it's
it's a mammography
that is where we are today the so-called
leaders have escaped from the country
they have fled
and the the economy is ruined uh
there is no more fuel in the country
maybe there's a food crisis what not the
country has been totally ruined so that
is what's happening right now and the
minister of external affairs in india
has uh
has put out a statement today let me see
what it looks like
let me see what the statement is
let me put it up let me put up the
twitter account of the
ministry of external affairs india
let's
see what we have to say about this what
the indian government has to say
uh yes so this is the statement
it says that it's it's in response to
various media queries about the
situation uh so the official statement
from our external office ministry is
that india is sri lanka's closest
neighbor and the two countries share
deep civilizational bonds
we are aware of the many challenges that
sri lanka is people have been facing
and we have stood with the sri lankan
people as they have tried to overcome
this difficult period
in pursuance with the stre of the
central place that sri lanka occupies in
our neighborhood first policy
india has extended this year itself an
unprecedented support of over 3.8
billion us dollars
for ameliorating the serious economic
situation in sri lanka we continue to
follow closely this recent developments
in sri lanka
india stands with the people of sri
lanka as they seek to realize their
aspirations for prosperity
and progress through democratic means
and values established institutions and
constitutional framework so this is a
very uh diplomatic statement obviously
we will have to use terms words like uh
democracy and
democratic means and values and
establish new institutions on
constitutional framework and all that
so that is the situation in sri lanka
now what exactly has happened there i
mean a lot of indian geopolitical
commentators are blaming everything on
china i agree that the chinese have uh
played the there's a the usual trick of
the
checkbook diplomacy the debt trap
diplomacy and they have managed to
acquire the hambantota port in the south
of the country
on a 99 year lease and all that but i
did i would disagree with those who said
that the chinese are responsible for the
complete devastation of the of the sri
lankan economy that is not true
lots of people in india are saying this
very very
prominent commentators and all that the
chinese are not entirely responsible for
the for the complete disaster that the
sri lankan economy has become
here's
the truth
over the last half century the imf the
international monetary fund
has given sri lanka
loans
sixteen loans not one not two not three
not five or ten sixteen loans
big loans sizable massive loans
now the imf
or the world bank these two institutions
are essentially you could say arms of
the west
they are extensions of western foreign
policy essentially u.s foreign policy
and the when the imf gives you a loan
that loan has a number of conditions
attached to it
you don't get to use the money in any
way you want they will tell you how to
use the money
so
the first thing i mean for india for
instance india in 1991 92 was going
bankrupt the government had ruined the
economy and india was forced to open up
its economy in exchange for imf on world
bank assistance
so the condition was that india will
open up its economy india will become
slowly a free market economy and it will
allow
western companies to enter india and do
business and so on so forth right so
similarly for sri lanka a
large number of so-called liberal
reforms or neo-liberal reforms were
imposed
as conditions
as part of these loans and these are
essentially the key causes of the
current crisis in sri lanka
and once again they ruined the
agricultural sector as well there is
this indian lady called vandana shiva
who uh
who essentially advised the sri lankan
government to give up all uh
uh
to to be to go into organic farming no
more
pesticides
no more uh fertilizers you know chemical
fertilizers go completely organic that
ruined the agricultural sector of sri
lanka that's why there are there are so
many protests happening in the
netherlands right now
because the netherlands government is
trying to impose those sort of
conditions on their own farmers and
that's why there is this massive the
entire country is essentially paralyzed
right now
but the sri lankan government
took this whole they swallowed this
whole syria and they they ruined their
entire agricultural sector which is why
now they're in this food crisis they
have to import food from other countries
india has been providing a significant
amount of assistance
so i would say yes the chinese do they
did play their role but the major
role the key role was played by the imf
and
their interference in sri lanka's
internal affairs so right now the sri
lanka
the country is in crisis i don't know
what is the way forward india obviously
will monitor the monitor this situation
closely if things go really bad india
will have to deal with the refugee
crisis because where else will they go
where else would the sri lankans go
they will have to come to india
for for refuge if things are really bad
in the country so it is not something
that india would want
we don't want uh it is not in india's
interest to to absorb lots of refugees
if such a situation were to arise so
india needs to monitor the situation
very carefully
and uh yeah i would not make any
recommendations as to what the
uh
future course of action should be but
yeah we need to monitor this character
carefully and take the right steps at
the right time
in order to help the people of sri lanka
okay kostov says
what's the current status quo in the
russian russia ukraine conflict when
will the war completely end will there
be any peace treaty signed between
ukraine and russia
as sanctions are backfiring on the west
record high inflation in europe in the
us the ruble is the strongest performing
currency despite so many sanctions in
diplomatic isolation
yes your observations are correct there
is record inflation in europe
there is terrible inflation in the
uh u.s prices prices gasoline prices are
across ten dollars which is incredible
it's it's a time for great hardship it's
a time of great heart great hardship in
the us in western europe
and russia the russian currencies is
extremely strong right now it's way
stronger than it was at the beginning of
the war in february right february 24 is
the day the wall of war officially
started the west imposed a
bucket load of sanctions this through
through the entire kitchen sink at the
russian economy and yet the russian
ruble emerged out of it for very simple
reasons
the russians
pegged the ruble to to gold
they have a sizable amount of gold
reserves and they pegged the price of
the ruble to the to the price of gold
very simple and they demanded
they are the major supplier of gas
to europe europe depends on russia for
their energy security for their for
their heating and all that europe is a
cool place they need that
so the russians demanded that all
payments for gas be done in russian
rubles so there's a demand for rubles
and the ruble automatically becomes
valuable and its price rises so the
ruble is currently the one of the most
one of the strongest performing
currencies in the world right now
and all the sanctions have backfired
obviously there will be some some effect
but
clearly the russians planned for this
they anticipated everything the west
would do everything the west would throw
at them and they are doing well
this has been something they have
planned for a long time very clearly
very clearly
so uh what's the status quo the status
quo is that the donbass region is in
russian control
uh much of southern ukraine is in
essentially
russia is in control of a quarter
approximately one-fourth of ukraine
which is a territory that is at least as
large as bangladesh or pakistan
that's how it is that's a that's a
massive territorial gain right now the
military uh
obviously there's a war going on
and it's proceeding
there is no time constraint or time
pressure on russia
the if there was if their economy was
crumbling then there would be a massive
time constraint and time pressure on
russia they would have to finish what
they set out to finish in a certain
amount of time as quickly as possible
but there is no time pressure on russia
so they are taking the time and they
will achieve their objectives at their
own
pace
so what are the objectives uh obviously
they want to re-integrate their the
russian-speaking russian-majority
regions
into russian territory maybe they will
create independent republics initially
and after 10 20 years they will absorb
them into russia something like that
and they want to ensure that the
uh
the nazi elements of ukrainian society
are essentially neutralized in some way
or the other
so that's where we are the
the fighting is going on
uh the russians are using old school
tactics in ukraine it's not a high-tech
war it's not a war that fought that's
fought with drones and all that yet
drones are being used by the russians
uh but the fighting is more or less old
old-school old style
so the russians are
fighting at a distance
they are not fighting face to face with
ukrainians the ukrainians have massive
army first of all understand that the
ukrainian armed forces number more than
50 60 divisions
they have their army is greater than the
entire armed forces of western europe
combined
that's how big the ukrainian army is or
was and they have significant amount of
reserves as well it's a very very
powerful military a very large military
and
they also have a very strong industrial
base technological base they possibly
could have the
ability to even
create nuclear weapons possibly they may
have it so that's so that's the
situation so the russians are
confronting a very big very big army but
they're dealing with it and the
ukrainians have no
uh
they don't really have any response to
what the russians are doing and there is
no way the west canada can get involved
there is no way nato can get involved
the russians have not even thrown 10
percent of their of their air force into
this they still have a massive amount of
reserves left behind
it's just about
10 percent of the russian uh armed
forces that are currently involved in
the fighting so that's where we are
eventually i would expect that the
entirety of the black sea coast will be
annexed by russia of course we have we
have we have to take a look at the map
how can i talk about this without the
map so please uh give me a second let me
bring in the map
where is the map here's the map
where's the map
here it is so
sorry yeah all right so uh here is
ukraine
and the entire eastern part of ukraine
the luhansk donetsk region is gone so
first of all crimea has already gone
and eventually i would expect the
russians would want to take miku live
and odessa as well
so the entire black sea coast will
eventually most likely be under russian
control there's nobody who can stop this
the russians will do it at their own
pace
and
i would expect that eventually even
ukraine would
either be taken over by russia
or
a puppet government would be installed
there and
the country would essentially be
partitioned there would be a trump state
which is western ukraine which would be
left behind and it would be essentially
powerless and it would be something that
would never be allowed to
enter nato and ever be a threat to
russia
so the long-term objectives remain the
same
and that is what's going to have
happened eventually so it's a long
drawn-out war it's not a very hot war
very fast-paced war but the russians are
very clear about what their objectives
are they want to ensure that this part
of the world is never a threat for them
again
and that's what they are going towards
they will
neutralize the ukrainian armed forces
and
long term look it looks like they will
partition the country and install a
puppet government in the part of the
country that they are interested in
that's what could happen and it is what
all the other nations are currently
looking at this with great interest
especially the various militaries in the
world are watching this with great
interest because
we are witnessing new forms of warfare
are drones effective
in this war well not very much what are
the tactics that work people have been
saying that the russian tanks don't work
the russians tanks are doing just fine
yeah obviously you will have some losses
and all that but what tactics are
succeeding what stack what tactics are
not working
so all that is being currently very
keenly observed by the entire world and
the lessons will be taken forward in
future conflicts in this decade i hope
there's no conflict but
human history tells you otherwise our
history tells us otherwise so in future
conflicts these
lessons will be applied
so that's what's happening
okay man vashishta says in one of your
podcasts with ranvir alaba you said that
the main reason why russia defeated nazi
germany was due to their massive numbers
of reserve personnel but then why was
russia not able to defeat a small
country like finland
during the winter war of 1939-40
okay i did say that
russia was able to defeat nazi germany
in operation barbarossa 1941
41 most likely 41.
because of their massive numbers of
reserve personnel they threw incredible
numbers of russian soldiers into this
meat grinder horrible
they were able to defend the country
at the cost of oceans of blood
it was terrible but it worked eventually
they took berlin
yeah so that's what they did and that is
indeed the case now what about finland
let's take a look at the map once again
same part of the world
so
what happened in finland
why did russia go to war
with finland
so in 1939 1940 during the second world
war there was this brief winter war
three four months around three months
between russia and finland
and the russian object see the the
reason why this war happened the
russians initiated the war
it happened in this region and the
russians were worried that
this great city sang petersburg st
petersburg which was then known as
leningrad it was too close to the
finland border
and it could possibly be threatened by
uh
through
from across the border from from finland
the the border was different at the time
it was much closer to the city of saint
petersburg and the russians saw it as a
very major threat that maybe
a hostile power could use the territory
of finland to to launch an attack
on saint petersburg and to
preclude that they proactively went to
war with finland that's what happened
the war lasted about uh
about three months roughly look it up
the exact dates it's about three months
as far as i to the best of my
recollection
now
at the end of the war the russians
gained about the finland finland lost
about 10 percent of its territory so it
is not correct to say that the russians
lost the war
what is being said here that uh russia
was not able to defeat a small country
like finland the russians achieved their
objectives and they exceeded their
objectives
they acquired more territory from
finland than they wanted to
they exceeded their objectives the
current finland russia border is a
reflection of what happened during that
war
it is true that the russians suffered
far more casualties than finland
i think the russian army lost five times
as many soldiers as the finland army so
yes that was not a very good performance
uh they did not do well the army
obviously
did not do a good job but they did
eventually
achieve their objectives and surpass the
objectives
but the the consequence of this is that
the the army didn't clearly did not do a
very good job they lost so many people
and that encouraged adolf hitler to
eventually in 1941 launch operation
barbarossa aimed at
conquering russia
so the performance of the russian army
the ussr army in this war uh was not
good
so hitler was encouraged by that at that
time
russia and germany the ussr and germany
had a
an agreement the molotov ribbentrop pact
so this pact was about essentially about
non-aggression and about dividing a pool
and
so they both agreed that they would take
roughly half of half of poland and as
soon as the germans invaded poland the
soviets also invaded poland from the
east
and they divided the poland
and this agreement lasted until 1941
when
adolf hitler gave up his
attacks on england
temporarily
and turned his direction
eastwards to the ussr eventually it was
a disastrous move and it culminated in
the
uh
defeat of germany defeat of nazi germany
so to answer your question it is not
correct to say that russia was not able
to defeat the finland they defeated
finland they achieved and exceeded their
objectives for the war but yes they they
lost
way more soldiers than the finns did
because the fans understood
their terrain much better than the
russians and they were prepared for such
invasion and eventuality so so the
objective of the of the ussr was not to
take over the entirety of finland it was
to ensure that there was more
territory available
and and that
more territory was taken into russia and
that any potential threat to saint
petersburg
was neutralized so that was the
objective and they achieved the
objective
okay srijit says in 1914 the sms emden
bombed madras harbor it's now chennai it
was then known as madras
is it true that an indian revolutionary
in berlin champakraman pillai was the
mastermind behind this what was his
hitler's view
on british rule in india are there any
instances where he helped indian
revolutionaries
okay so let's take once again a look at
the facts what actually happened for
that we have to go back to the to the
map
here's the map so now
we know where madras
the earth's wild city of madras was it's
now called chennai it's here in
southern india off the bay of bengal the
the great kalingama sagar
so this uh
this this ship
the sms emden
was uh
originally
harbored it it was a
birthed at the port of king dao
in china kingdom used to be a german
occupied territory at the time
china was under uh various parts of
china where under european occupation so
king dao the city of kingdom the
portuguese was
it was then called ching dao i think
thing tower or something like that it
was at that time
in under the possession of germany and
the germans had a number of uh naval
warships
in this port so the sms enden was a
german light cruiser or medium cruiser
one of these two things so it's a
medium-sized battleship right so when
the first world war broke out in 1914
uh eventually happened is that australia
and new zealand
uh grabbed various german possessions in
the pacific ocean the germans were in
control of various islands
in this region the marshall islands was
one of them i believe and so on in the
south pacific region the australians and
the new zealanders they took over these
islands
and germany lost those possessions
so uh the germans what they did was they
they
launched
this ship took off from from tsingtao
the captain of the ship was called
formula
and he
essentially waged a three four month
lone battle all across this region so
let me take you
let me show you
where this happened one second uh the
the the voyage of the of the sms mdn in
the various engagements it
took so take a look at this
so this essentially
is the
long convoluted route that this ship
took
and it uh engaged lots of targets it
sunk from some vessels
on september 23 1914 it bombed the port
city of madras
it uh did it saw some action off the
coast of burma
it was in the maldives and the electrode
islands the chagos archipelago
and eventually
in november
2014 it
was destroyed it it was run aground
in the cocos and killing islands that's
what happened right
so on september 23 this ship bombed
the port city of madras it it set fire
to
the oil tanks over there and
yeah so that is what happened these are
the fact that we have at our
disposal
so what we know
is that this ship was in thing tau
in 1914
and uh over the course of three four
months it saw this action it was
eventually destroyed now the captain of
the ship was uh carl von miller when the
ship was destroyed in the cocoa and
peeling islands the
sailors were injured
were taken to australia
the sailors were not injured were taken
i believe to malta
and these people were eventually
repatriated to germany in 1920
in 1920 right
now we know that
mr champa karaman pillai was present in
berlin in 1914
he was in berlin in 1914. if he had been
on the sms emblem he would have been in
cintao
in 1914 and he would whoever he would
have not been able to return to berlin
until most likely 1920
right so it is clear from these facts
the best evidence that we have at our
hands
that it doesn't appear like uh champagne
pillai was on that ship
and if it was not on the trip
then
how would he mastermind this entire
operation the mastermind behind this
entire operation was the captain of the
ship carl von miller
that was a mastermind and
he would he would not need the presence
of champa karma pillai to get the idea
of bombing madras
and showing the people of india that the
british should be defeated
so that's what i can tell about you uh
about this matter i have seen no
evidence whatsoever that champakaram
pillai was on the ship or was the master
behind behind the operation
right i i know that some people have
claimed i believe his family has claimed
that he may have been behind this but
maybe it's possible i don't think it's
completely impossible but the evidence
for this doesn't exist
so that's what i can say
what was hitler's view about british
rule in india you know
hitler actually had a good opinion about
the british he kind of admired the
british
uh
but of course they went to war against
each other so he
sought to defeat them
uh
and what was his view about british rule
in india well your enemies enemies my
friend and that's why he he
received subhashin the rebels warmly and
then he recommended him to go to japan
and carry the operation forward so
obviously hitler would have been happy
if the british rule in india would have
ended at the time
so
that is the situation are there any
instances where he helped indian
revolutionaries uh to the best of my
knowledge i only know about the
interaction between hitler and mr bose
and
he received mr bose warmly and
he hosted him in in germany during the
length of mr bose's stay there and
eventually he recommended to mr bose to
go to japan
and take up action i mean take up the
course of indian independence from from
that staging base so that's eventually
what happened and that's what we know
about it
okay kinshuk says you said in a previous
episode that the usa and the ussr got
there acquired their rocket technology
from
with the help of german scientists they
acquired it from nazi germany
essentially yeah so my question is where
did the germans get this technology from
please answer
okay so
at the end of world war ii
a large number of german space i mean
rockets scientists and engineers
including fernando von braun
were captured and taken prisoner by the
americans
and they were then
brought to the u.s they were brought to
the u.s and it was their expertise
and they the americans also captured
some of the
german ballistic missiles the v2
ballistic missiles the germans are the
pioneers of not only cruise missile
technology but also ballistic missile
technology
nobody had built these kinds of missiles
before
so the americans acquired
at least one v2 missile if not more
they brought it to the us
and the rocket was tested from there and
it was all of this that gave rise to the
u.s space program
this was called operation paper clip
operation paperclip so it was german
technology german scientific and
engineering expertise that built the u.s
space program and
built nasa essentially
verna von braun was eventually the head
of nasa
he was for a very long time a prisoner
essentially in the us but he rose to
become the head of nasa and he was the
man there was the brain behind the
saturn v rocket which took neil
armstrong and other people to to the
moon
so yes the americans acquired all of
their rocket technology from the germans
the russians
they took they captured
whatever other scientists german
scientists they could they brought them
to russia and that is what gave rise to
the russian space program
right
yuri gagarin was the first human being
in space and so on so forth
so yes the americans and the russians
the ussr the soviets they acquired their
rocket technology from the from the
germans they did not have their own
technology and the chinese acquired
their rocket technology from the
russians so that also has its origin in
germany so the question is
where did the germans get this
technology from well the obvious answer
is come on it's aliens don't you think
okay to be um
yeah it's not aliens look
the germans desi developed the
technology on their own
that's what they did
um
see in 1971
germany was born as a nation it was
unified from various uh
what you could say uh
various kingdoms essentially
by the great
chancellor
bismarck
and bismarck was the true power in
germany even though there was a king the
kaiser
the kaiser came second his father was
there and so on
so the true power the true uh power in
germany was otto on bismarck and
bismarck instituted a number of
far-reaching reforms in germany after
1971. he reformed the industry germany
overnight within the span of a decade
become became the major industrial power
in europe it became the engine that
drove europe and the european economy it
became the most powerful economy in
europe
they
developed a massive technologically
advanced industrial base
they
they built very
good universities their scientific
education was
the best of the entire world most likely
and that is why all the
all the uh breakthroughs
in physics
happen from germany the initial
breakthroughs whether it is the
discovery of the quantum nature of the
world
max planck whether it is relativity
albert einstein and for the development
of quantum theory all of that happened
in germany because they had the best
education system they're the best
technological base they had the best
researchers
and if you are good you are promoted
there was no
there was complete meritocracy there was
no nepotism all that so that's why the
best minds were attracted towards
germany
and there was a flowering of of
technology and science in germany and
that is what gave rise to the german
space program the missile program the
cruise missiles uh the ballistic
missiles all of that and of course the
the incredible aircraft fighter aircraft
that the germans
developed over the years they also
developed the first jet aircraft the jet
fighter the germans and uh if you look
at world war ii some of the best fighter
planes and other planes were german
plays the there's two cars the meshes
smith's the fork of wolfe's and and so
many more the henkels bombers
and so much more so the germans
acquired this technology by developing
it themselves nobody gifted the
technology to them it's not like some
aliens came and said hi my german
friends take this technology it's not
like that they develop the technology
from scratch
like india did later india
nobody getting india rocket technology
isro the scientists at isro
developed the technology from scratch
so did the japanese scientists nobody
help them they developed their rocket
technology from scratch so germany
developed its rocket technology from
scratch so did india so did japan the
americans just acquired the german
technology and built upon that so did
the soviets so did the chinese i hope
that answers your question my good
friend
okay two questions by atharva
why do
uk prime ministers not last long
in india chief ministers and prime
ministers complete the full term mostly
but in the uk this doesn't happen
is it because of intra-party democracy
which is absent in indian parties the
second second question is in the uk how
much power does the crown hold
is it more powerful than the prime
minister's office do bureaucrats run the
country
okay so you have compared the situation
in the uk with india you know in the
1990s indian prime ministers came and
went like a merry-go-round
the indian
uh
parliamentary system is is is a copy
of the uk system the westminster system
it's an inherently unstable system
you had so many prime ministers who were
there for two months three months five
months whatever four months in the 1990s
in india
who comes to my mind
chandra shekhar
then the vajpayee government came and
fell in in a couple of weeks
it is an inherently unstable system it's
only now that you have a prime minister
that everybody wants to vote for and
that's why
he sweeps the elections
but
the indian
parliamentary system is inherently
unstable you need somebody like mr modi
if you don't have somebody like that
then you will have coalition governments
which are inherently weak full of
infighting and they they can collapse at
any time so that is the situation that
you see in the uk right now
so the question is why do uk pms last
it's because the system is inherently
unstable
the uk
parliamentary system has evolved
slowly
essentially
over the course of the past 1000 years
it all began with the magna carta
the great charter of
the great charter right the magna carta
which which gave rights to people and do
various things like that you can go into
that in google google it
it begins with the domesday book the
magna carta reforms institute instituted
by william the conqueror who conquered
was the last foreign invader to
successfully conquer england in the year
1066 it starts from his reforms
eventually
uh
a parliament was constituted
so a few centuries later
uh there were
there were depositions of kings under
cromwell i believe
not the first cromwell the second
cromwell his great uncle is a great
nephew or something and so on it's a
long story
it's uh
so
the question really is that if you have
a country in which you have such an
inherently unstable system of governance
the the prime minister can't typically
doesn't last long
then then how is such a country able to
survive
so i think the system is designed to be
unstable because the true power always
had to reside with the with the crown
and the the royalty
the kings and queens of england did not
want other people to become too powerful
that's why the the system was designed
that way that it would never be too
powerful nobody would have too much
power nobody would stay in power too
long even if they stayed in power there
were checks and balances the house of
lords is an unelected body
it's not an elected body the upper house
of parliament it's the lords nowadays
they don't have much power
but
in the past they did have a lot of power
they could veto any act or any any
legislation that the lower uh the house
of commons would pass
in the past right
and
the bureaucracy obviously has a huge
amount of power the unelected
bureaucracy in england in the uk
uh
the attitude of the bureaucracy is that
prime ministers come and go but we are
there forever
and they can if they wish stifle
any uh policy measures that the prime
minister may institute
they may simply make it make these
measures or policy measures ineffective
if they want
so the real question is who controls the
bureaucracy so it's a very opaque
obscure system we don't really know
where the real power lies
uh the official uh
stand is that the uh monarchy in england
the crown is just a figurehead a title
position it doesn't have any power
and so on that's what is claimed but we
don't quite know what the situation is
clearly the prime ministers don't have
much power prime ministers come and go
in such an unstable system there's
nothing a prime minister
a prime minister could do for too long i
mean the latest example is mr johnson
boris johnson who was there for a while
before him it was that lady whose name i
forget i mean these people they come and
go you don't even remember the names the
last i mean there's this guy called
brown
um
and so on so people have come and go
they keep coming and going just like in
japan in japan also apart from mr shinzo
abe the prime minister just come and go
come and go you don't even remember the
names i remember a few names like
yasu yasuhiro nakasone
koizumi two three names i remember the
others are all anonymous and similarly
it's the same for england for for the uk
so clear see
here's the thing about the world
there is something called
official positions and there's something
that's unofficial or undeclared
there are extra democratic extra
governmental extra constitutional power
networks and power centers in every
country in the world
in every nation in the world there are
power networks and power centers that
are un that are extra constitutional
extra democratic and extra governmental
right to understand what these are you
have to understand what is the true
nature of power which is a whole
different topic which you can't explain
in five minutes
so you have to understand that properly
and when you understand that it becomes
very clear that many of these so-called
positions like prime ministers actually
etc they don't really hold
too much real power
in the uk
the prime minister is a ceremonial
position essentially
essentially
and the prime minister's actual function
is to
is to distract the public's attention
from where the real power lies
in the words of one of their own writers
who wrote about something else but it's
very apt in this in this case
right
so the prime minister's job is to
distract attention from where the true
power lies and mr boris johnson did a
great job of that he was very
entertaining
very very entertaining i mean no ma you
may agree or disagree with his policies
but it was fun to watch
so that's how it is
the crown may still hold a lot of power
the bureaucrats certainly
hold more power than the government than
the leave than the prime minister and so
on but
where does the real power lie that's
quite that's kind of
not very visible it's kind of opaque
obscure the way it has been designed to
be
okay anish says
is there any chance at all of us which
means india getting the permanent seat
in the u.n security council anymore
because i feel other than russia and
france no one will be in favor of us
being the sixth member even if the u.s
and the uk are china will never be
so in which scenario
can india
get a permanent seat in the u.n security
council or is it just a dream or a wish
that will never be fulfilled
and at the current status power and
influence that india has do we truly
deserve it right now
okay
u.n security council so as we know so
what is the united nations to understand
all of this you have to understand what
is the united nations and the united
nations security council
the united nations was born it was it
was formed
in
1945 i think if i don't if i recall
correctly
at the end of world war ii
so
it was formed it was constituted before
world war two ended but when the writing
on the wall was already visible the
germans were about to lose they were
doing very badly and the japanese would
soon follow suit so the united nations
was created and membership was given to
all those who declared war on germany
and japan
so suddenly a whole lot of countries
across the world declared war officially
on germany and japan also i suppose
these are just verbal declarations it
did not mean that they're there to
actually send soldiers but you do that
then you get a membership in the united
nations so it was a club
of those who won
in the united st security council
is another body which has a number of
members but the core group the five
members the five permanent members were
the actual victors of world war two the
allies the united states the uk
france
who's the fourth one the ussr yes these
are the four victorious powers and the
fifth one they were wondering whom they
should give it to and they wanted to
give it to india and there's a whole
story there the chinese were also
involved in that but not
the communist party the other one you
know
it's a whole story there you can look it
up so they wanted to give this seat to
india and mr nehru as we know as is
established as is very well documented
by multiple sources he refused multiple
times 1950 he refused 1953 he refused
1955 also he refused and eventually it
was given to china
right
so today today india wants it but today
nobody wants to give it to india the
chinese have a veto they have this very
powerful position well so to some extent
it's powerful and they don't want india
to be elevated to the status of an equal
to them and of course india is currently
not an equal to china
india is certainly india the indian
economy has exceeded that of france in
the uk for sure as far as i remember
but india's economy is still much
smaller than that of china or the us
and russia has inherited the seat of the
ussr so there is there is a situation
right now and none of these people would
want to relinquish their power or to or
to dilute the power by bringing in new
members
so some of these nations may verbally
say that we are in favor of
adding india to this but it won't happen
most likely
so
do we truly deserve it
if the if the uk deserves it if france
deserve it deserves it so does india so
we certainly would be deserving
considering that the uk and the france
and france are part of it
but we is this just a dream or a wish
that will never be fulfilled
if india does rise
if india does rise to
a 10 trillion dollar economy or more
than that we want more than that
then it may happen
but before that the un will have to be
reconstituted properly the un is an
obsolete body it's an obsolete
organization it is a remnant
of the
post-world war ii era that's what it is
so it it is a snapshot in time of the
the situation in the post-world war two
era it is obsolete today the world has
changed so maybe in this decade or in
the next decade the world order will
totally be reorganized one hopes it
happens through peaceful means one does
not want warfare but who knows
eventually the world order will change
like officially and then maybe a new u.n
will be constituted and this this entire
business will be disbanded
if that's that sort of thing happens
india will certainly
rise to this sort of position like being
a permanent member on whatever new
security council or whatever it is that
is
formed at that time but as of today
there is no chance of india getting in
so don't hope for the
thing for the next five to ten years at
least india has to rise first
to a significant
position in
world affairs
okay the iedk says how did
how were princely states how did
princely states
okay
how did princely states rule in british
india were the kings just
titles like today
or did they have some actual political
power in their respective
geographical areas
right good question i think i may have
spoken about this before but let's take
it up again so
the british took absolute control of
india
in 1857
1857 was the war of independence
much of india rose up against british
occupation
and there was a time when things were in
balance but eventually the british were
able to prevail
and
they whoever fought the british
the various so-called uh kingdoms in
india
who fought against the british they were
all defeated and they those
lineages were ended
then what the british did
is that
there was such a massive country to
govern a massive landmass the entire
indian subcontinent
from present day pakistan all the way to
burma
it is difficult to rule
such a massive subcontinent without uh
without putting on putting on a certain
kind of show so what they did was they
destroyed all of these families all of
the all the royal families that had
fought against them and then they
installed puppets in their place
and some of these royal families made
compromises with the british and they
agreed to
serve the british
after 1857
every single royal family
served the british
how what does it mean
all of these kingdoms were then given
the name of princely states by the
british
in each of these princely states
there was a british political officer
a british
political officer
who would tell the local prince or
whatever it was
what sort of policies they must
implement
the
rules or the laws that were in power
that were enforced
were
british
rules or laws
eventually the whole legal system was
created by the british which we which is
still followed in india
so these princely states the rulers were
essentially agents of the british they
were puppets of the british
they collected taxes there there would
be a british collector also
a collector of money
even today in india there is a
possession of district collector my
question is what does the district
collector collect today
what does he collect or she collect
why is that person still called a
collector
why can't you call him or her a district
administrator or district magistrate
they have not even changed the name of
the title
district collector so all of these
princely states they would have a
collector who was essentially an
extortionist
these kings and queens whoever it was
would
extract taxes from the population from
their population from the from the
people on behalf of the british hand it
over to the so-called collector who
would then
and it would be used to enrich the east
india company and eventually the british
raj there would also be a political
agent who would ensure that the british
policies were followed by these rulers
so essentially these rules were nothing
but puppets
some of them actively and happily
collaborated with the british some of
them were undeserving people who were
put in power as puppets after the
british killed off the actual kings and
queens
many such puppets were put in power i
will not name them because it will
offend some people
and some of these royal families
made a compromise in order to serve
their people somehow one of the
major examples that comes to my mind is
the travancore royal family
the travancore royal family was also a
princely state and they also were
essentially under the thumbs of the
british and yet they did
the people and the in the country great
service they had never allowed the
british to know
that the great shri padmanaba swami
temple has an incredibly enormous
treasure within
if the british knew about this they
would have looted everything
that treasure still exists it is still
there in the walls of the sri padmana
swami temple
its value is
estimated to be in excess of one
trillion dollars not rupees
dollars some some geniuses are gonna
come and come in the comments and say no
it's rupees not dollars no
it is estimated to be in excess
of one trillion dollars in value and
some of the vaults have not even been
opened yet and this these these this
treasure that's in this temple goes back
thousands of years
yeah so the travancore royal family
never allowed the british to come to
know to find out that there's this
massive
treasure in the temple
and
so that is a great thing they did so
many of these royal families were
actually trying their best to serve
their people they were not all traitors
they were not all collaborated
collaborators but some of these
so-called princely states and their
royal families were puppets installed by
the british and they were totally
completely beholden to the british for
their power and position not powered by
the possession and prestige
and they were true servants of the
british so some
served the people some served the
british that's how it was but they none
of them had any actual power
none of them had an actual power they
were simply
agents of the british in a variety of
ways that is the truth after 1857 all of
the royal families all of the princely
states were nothing but british puppets
and that's the truth
okay rinegan says
what is the origin of the mates are they
invaders from china
who did atrocities on the bishnupriyas
it's written everywhere on the in on the
internet that they invaded manipur
around 350 years ago
or is it propaganda against the metha
people just like the aryan invasion myth
okay first of all to the viewers who may
not know who are the methi people the
methi people are the people of manipur
where is manipur i i suppose many people
would not know where it is so let us go
to the map where's the map here's the
map let's go to the map and take a look
at where manipur is in case some of you
don't know manipur is in the far east of
india it is to the south of what is now
called nagaland and to the north of
mizoram
can you see manipur written here
manipur is to the west of burma
mar
the capital of manipur is
so this
is now a state in india it was once one
of the greater princely kingdoms one of
the great kingdoms in india
and the question is that has been asked
is what is the origin of the materials
the methods are the people of manipur
uh they
they follow two religions the origin
religion is called
some everything is in ism nowadays in
english but the worship of the great god
sanama he and the pantheon of gods
around that
and later on um
during the time of the the king
one of the kings of
vaishnavism became the official
state state religion so to say gaudiya
vaishnavism which was brought into
manipur by this individual called
chaitanya mahaprabhu right
so about three or four centuries ago
vaishnavism became a big deal in manipur
eventually most people of manipur
practiced a syncretic version of
syncretic mixture of sanama ism and
gaudiya vaishnavism very similar to the
situation that you have in japan where
most people a century ago practiced
shinto as well as buddhism shinto
is the original
uh
culture religion whatever you call it of
of japan buddhism came in about 1500
years ago
from via china
so shinto is
the original writers of
the original authors who wrote about
shinto in japan
they essentially said that shinto is
like japanese hinduism and buddhism is
like a
simplified version of that
so that's a different story so the
maithis are the people of manipur
they are the ones who practice sunamism
and gaudiya vaishnavism either or
or both
and the question is what is the origin
of the media people are they invaded
from china
who did atrocities on the manipuris
or is it propaganda i have never read
anywhere that the vishnu the maithis did
atrocities against the british
and they invaded from china three years
ago
the royal chronicle of of manipur of the
of the kings of manipur is called the
chaitarol kombaba
it
is a detailed chronology
of the entire uh
lineage of the ning thoujam dynasty it
dates back to about 2000 years before
today in one version and in the other
version it dates back to 3500 years
before today
so it's clear that the mayday people
have been in manipur most likely for at
least three and a half thousand years
so this 350 years ago i don't know what
that is
who comes up with these ridiculous
stories the metis are the two
inhabitants and the true natives of the
people of the of manipur
and they have been there for thousands
of years
so i don't know what what stories
are nowadays being propagated but there
is no such thing who are the vishnu
prayers
so about
about roughly 200 years ago there was
the seven years of devastation of
manipur the burmese invaded manipur and
assam and they did they essentially
tried to wipe out the manipuri people
the meti people they essentially
indulge in genocide the burmese against
manipur so lots of manipuri's escape
from manipur some of them went to assam
some of them went into bengal
many of them uh live in places like
silet in bangladesh today which was then
part of india part it was it was part of
bengal um many of these people
manipuri's maites they escaped into
other places like tripura assam etc and
eventually these people came to be known
as vishnu priyani police right so
that's what it is there is
i don't know where who comes up with
these ridiculous claims that the methods
did atrocities in the vishnu prayer
manipuri that's nonsense okay so uh the
origin of the mate is before three and a
half thousand years i i don't know i
think we would need to do genetic
research
to
go to the bottom of that i'm not sure
that has been done but
the metis have most likely been in
manipur for at least three and a half
thousand years so
so these stories are totally completely
false and total propaganda
the reformer says kung fu is a chinese
martial art which has an indian origin
okay
you said it reached china along with the
buddhists how come a religion that is
all about peace and non-violence spread
a fighting style
this is one of the great myths that
prevalent that is prevalent about indian
culture that india the indian culture is
all about non-violence and never
fighting back and all that
here's how
i've spoken about this in the past and
speaking about it again today here is
how kung fu reached china
uh
about 1600 or so years ago
look up the exact details on the website
of the shaolin temple
okay
so about 1600 or so years ago roughly
there is a time when buddhism was and
indian culture was being
becoming very popular in china it
started with the kushan era
the great emperor of india kanishkap
is the one who started it all he started
sending not
along with the trade delivery
delegations to china he started sending
scholars
vedic scholars buddhist scholars etc and
that's how indian culture started
entering china and the chinese were
intrigued and they really liked it and
then what happened is that many chinese
kings
started sending ambassadors to india
requesting indian rulers to send more
scholars with so with who could
translate sanskrit texts into chinese
so lots of indian scholars went there
now about like i said about 1600 years
or so ago one of the indian scholars who
went there was called buddha bhadra
he went to this place to this region in
china the local king
built a a temple a monastery for this
indian guru called buddha bhadra where
he could stay in peace and translate all
the various sanskrit sutras into
chinese died after a few years and in
replacement a new monk went there who
was called bodhidharma he is most likely
somebody who went from southern india
most likely we not quite sure but most
likely he was from southern india
bodhidharma reaches this place and he
finds that this place is in a forested
region and lots of bandits they raid the
place from time to time they beat up the
monks and steal all the provisions
so bodhidharma what he did is he said we
will do all the all the culture stuff
later first let me teach you how to
defend yourself
defend yourselves so he taught these
chinese monks
the an ancient indian art of self
defense which was based on based in yoga
so it was an ancient martial art of
india based in yoga that he taught that
to the chinese
and it eventually came to be known as
kung fu this was the shaolin temple the
shaolin monastery but the dharma is the
first patriarch of the shaolin temple
right and if you go to the shaolin
temple today on a hill which overlooks
the temple there is a giant statue of
this great indian teacher bodhidharma
who not only taught dhyan
to the chinese but he also taught kung
fu
and he taught this indian version indian
form of meditation called dhyana
meditation
to the chinese and the chinese
eventually spread it to japan
further east
and the chinese called dhyana chan in
the japanese they eventually ended up
calling it zen so zen buddhism then
meditation it called all came from india
so that is the story of the origin of
kung fu it it originates in india the
original martial arts art is lost
india has lost it but the chinese have
developed it further they call it kung
fu
so it origin is from india the question
is how come a religion all about peace
and non-violence spread a fighting style
so the highest
um
the highest principle in all dharmic
belief systems in in in dharma itself
is
non-violence ahinsa ahinsa parma dharma
that is
the highest value in all forms of dharma
all flavors of dharma whether it is
jaina dharma or both the dharma or
various other forms of of what we call
hindu dharma right
ahinsa is always the parma dharma it
doesn't mean that when somebody comes
and beats you up you're gonna sit idle
and let that happen
what did lord krishna say
have you ever read the bhagavad gita
is is dharma about just
passive non-violence and passive
resistance no
the other aspect of dharma is that you
must destroy dharma by any means
necessary even if you have to break the
rules
that is what lord krishna thought
and lord krishna came a long time before
gotham buddha
and buddhism is nothing but one of the
flavors of dharma both the dharma the
dhamma whatever
right
and
so that's what it is
and that's why bodhidharma even though
he was a great guru
who supposedly taught buddhism he also
taught them how to defend themselves
because if you don't defend you defend
yourself you are breaking dharma you are
doing a dharma by allowing a dharma to
win you are also supporting a dharma
that's how it is so that's why buddhism
many buddhist kings were great warriors
come on
we all know that the the majapahit
empire in indonesia which was a hindu
empire was a was a great thalassocratic
empire the champa empire in in cambodia
and vietnam was a great maritime empire
and so on so forth look at the japanese
buddhist traditions
you had shinto which is the original
culture religion which is more like
hinduism than buddhism yeah
and then you have buddhism which appears
in japan about 1500 or so years ago it
becomes very very prevalent the two
traditions syncretize beautifully yeah
and the japanese warriors
the japanese warlords the shoguns
were buddhists
the japanese
warrior class you could call them the
japanese khatriyas the samurais
were buddhists they were proper
practicing buddhists
they had this code of honor called
bushido
it's about how a warrior should
conduct themselves
it's about honor it's about
it's about yeah it's about all that and
it is very much part of both the dharma
it is rooted in both the dharma in
buddhism
so it is completely incorrect to say
that buddhism
and dharma overall is about peace and
non-violence we value peace and
nonviolence we want peace and
non-violence it doesn't mean we're gonna
tolerate
violence you don't tolerate violence you
don't tolerate a dharma you have to
destroy dharma what does kali say
the mother goddess in hinduism
is is a very benevolent person whether
it is saraswati or lakshmi or durga or
whatever but she has the rudra roop
right what does kali do what does
chamunda do
so think about that
both the dharma buddhism is nothing but
a flavor of hinduism there is no real
difference the
the west
does it best does its best to emphasize
minute differences
mind you differences
but the similarities which are 99.9 of
the whole thing are ignored and that's
why people are brainwashing to believe
that buddhism and hinduism are different
and they have different concepts and
different uh
values and so on which is not the case
okay so that's about this question
okay aj raul says after watching the top
gun movie i'm really surprised as how a
f-14 jet
can
take on not one but three
fifth generation fighter jets which
appeared to be the super 57
uh can this really be possible also in
this aspect what kind of jet jets can
the lca pages come back combat
effectively now this is a very good
question first of all great movie
i watched it a while ago or maybe a
month or so ago the new top gun movie
uh it's the first movie that came out of
hollywood in a long long time that i
enjoyed it had no stupid messaging
moralizing morally you know that woke
variety and all the nonsense it was just
a clean
movie with good entertainment and a
reasonably good story
it was enjoyable i liked it which i was
very surprised by right
so in this movie you have this guy
maverick tom cruise who flies an f-14
fighter jet and takes out what yeah
maybe two or three
aircraft that look like sukhoi 57 which
is a fifth generation aircraft so is it
possible so let's understand what these
generations are the first generation of
fighter aircraft was the world war
ii fighter aircraft the
um
whatever was being was in use that at
that time the mustang the this the
spitfire i believe
and and so on the messer schmitz stukas
and so on i may i may have got some of
them wrong but the world war
ii aircraft were called the first
generation fighter vector
then you had the second generation
fighter aircraft which would get engine
fighters
the mig-21
is a second generation fighter aircraft
yeah and it's still in use in some
countries that you may know of
the third generation fighter aircraft
planes like the mig-23
fourth generation fighters are the f-16s
the f-14s the one that you are
mentioning here and so on then there is
something called the 4.5 generation
of fighter aircraft aircraft
which includes the mig-35
the lca pages the jf-17 and also the the
rafale the french aircraft so that's a
4.5 generation aircraft and the cages is
classified as a 4.5 generation aircraft
and then you have the latest
most advanced fighter aircraft which are
called the fifth generation fighter
planes
the first of those was the f-22 the
lockheed martin f-22
then you also have the f-35 the sukhoi
f-57
and the j-20 of china so these are fifth
generation fighter planes
so now the question is can
a
ff14 which is a fourth generation
fighter
take on and defeat a fifth generation
fighter like this like the sukhoi 57 no
it can't
the sukhoi 57 will not come anywhere
near
a fourth generation fighter plane it
will destroy it from 100 kilometers away
and the f-14 will not even know what
happened
that's how advanced a fifth generation
fighter plane is
the f-14 stands no chance whatsoever
against a fifth generation fighter
aircraft unless you're in very specific
terrain etc even then it's it's hard to
imagine that because uh
because fifth generation fighter
aircraft have certain systems like and
they have beyond visual range
missiles and so much more that they
don't need to come anywhere near
another fighter plane and engage in a
dogfight or whatever it's not necessary
they can destroy an f-14 from like 50 or
100 kilometers far far away
so yeah that was a leap of imagination
that was a suspension of disbelief in
the movie that an f-14 can take out
three sukhoi 57s which is like
impossible right the other question is
what kind of jets can the lca pages
combat effectively it can combat fourth
generation fighter planes and and and
older fighter planes
the lcd just would be a reasonably good
match for uh for a
mig-35
an f-14 an f-16 a mig-21 mig-23 etc
maybe it could even fight a rafale take
it
possibly
or definitely a jf-17 which the
pakistanis nowadays employ so that's the
kind of fighter plane
the
lca pages
can take on and defeat
it would be a stretch of imagination to
imagine that they just could defeat
a fifth generation fighter
and yet it may be possible if you have
sufficient numbers and so on but alone
a single
fourth generation aircraft can certainly
not take out a fifth generation fighter
plane yeah
so yeah so that is the situation that's
where we are
okay ashutosh says can india will india
be able to
will india be able to make the advanced
medium combat aircraft in this decade
so what is the amc it's the advanced
medium combat aircraft it is i believe
going to be a fifth generation fighter
plane with stealth elements so one of
the uh features of a fifth generation
fighter plane is it has stealth features
it has a very low radar cross section
the f22 f35 etc also have this feature
the j20 doesn't quite do a good job at
hiding itself but from behind it's it's
quite visible and so on from certain
angles it may be
able to give offer a low cross section
so the amca
is what is currently been being designed
in india it's going to be the next
generation of fighter aircraft
the first prototype test flight
is expected to be in 2024-25
around that time period
and i am
reasonably confident that they will be
able to uh
to make this time frame they would be
able to do it in this timeframe the
first test flight
and why am i confident it's because now
drdo and hindustan aeronautics limited
et cetera have a lot of expertise and
experience
through a lot of painful trial and error
of building a 4.5 generation aircraft
which is the lcds and the mach 1 and the
mark ii and various variants of that
right so they now know how to do it once
you do it
successfully on one occasion you can
then take it forward and it's much
easier to design a better aircraft which
is based on the previous one
so i think it should be not that
difficult now to take it forward and
design and build of
the first flying prototype of the amc in
the next two three years by 24 or 25
and then they will build they will test
it out they will see what are the
deficiencies where are the areas of
improvement they will make a second
prototype maybe a third one
and once the final design is locked the
final design is locked in after testing
everything out
then the aircraft will most likely enter
production by 2030.
so i
am pretty positive i'm pretty confident
that india will be able to
achieve this time frame will be able to
successfully produce the aircraft and
and bring it into serial production by
2030. i'm pretty confident about that
okay spywolf9 says f18 super hornet or
dassault rafale which one is the best
for the indian navy considering india's
trustworthy relations with france
and did we induct more american arms in
our ammunition okay i'll answer the
first part of the question which
aircraft could india go for so right now
india needs a number of
fighter planes for its new aircraft
carrier
i don't know what's the number india
seeking maybe 30 40 something like that
and there are a number of candidates in
the frame uh there was supposed to be a
a naval version of the tejas aircraft
but the navy did not go for that so now
that in in the future there could be a
twin engine deck based fighter a te dbf
which would be an advanced version of
the pages something to something similar
to the amca that also is in the in the
is is maybe something could be in the
pipeline right the amca but right now we
need a number of aircraft to fill the
gap temporarily maybe 20 30 aircraft
whatever the number is you can look it
up
and two of the best candidates are the
f-18 which is an american fighter plane
a twin engine fighter plane and the
rafale which is a french fighter plane
both of these uh
uh can land and take off from aircraft
carriers the f-18 super hornet seems to
have an advantage that you can fold its
wings
the rafale may not have that feature
does not have that feature
so what is the best bet for india
what should india go for the thing is
this you acquire the f-18
it's one more aircraft in your zoo
you can't have 500 different
aircraft in your zoo you have to keep
things simple if you acquire one more
model of aircraft one more species of
aircraft then you need another source of
spare parts
and things like that
it
introduces more complications
in your life
and in your in your
in your armed forces
ideally you don't want more than three
or four different kinds of aircraft
if you keep on buying different kinds of
planes from different places it it
messes things up it makes your life very
complex
so i would say we already have the rafal
we are already using it we haven't
reasonable amount of expertise or
fighters or our pilots know how to fly
it our engineers know how to service it
i think
one should go india should go with the
rafal and not with the f-18 i know the
americans won't like it but i think the
french are way more trustworthy we have
a longer
track record
of cooperation and strategic cooperation
and partnership with the french
we have acquired a number of submarines
from them we have acquired
we are on the on the verge of acquiring
rafales from them so i think it would be
best for india to stick with the rafale
which is a good aircraft very good
record proven aircraft and and use that
for the
for the stop as a stop gap solution for
our naval naval requirements so i would
say we should go for the rafale
abhishek says pranam this is my fourth
attempt all right i live in siliguri
west bengal a few years back the doklam
crisis scared us all here
what will happen if china decides to
bomb siliguri why is the government not
doing anything to secure silikuri okay
where is siliguri let's go to the map
where is siliguri the siliguri corridor
is also known as the chicken's neck
so here we have india
then we have the far east of india
and the small narrow piece of land that
connects the two
is called the siliguri corridor the
so-called chicken snack
right it's about 50 kilometers wide
and
yeah the chinese obviously will keep an
eye on this they will in in case of a
war between india and china the chinese
may want to cut it off to to take it
take it out so that they can
uh
bifurcate india and cut off the
northeast from the rest of the country
so that's that's
essentially a weak point
in india's geography
and the question is why is the
government not doing anything to secure
siliguri and you are somebody who lives
there so it's like this
just because you don't see lots of
soldiers in siliguri doesn't mean that
the government is doing nothing
to secure siliguri
you don't need to put
50 000 soldiers in siliguri to secure
siliguri you don't need to do that
how would one how would india
deal with it with a chinese attempt to
let's say
take over siliguri a tax siliguri bomb
siliguru whatever
india would deal with it
using air power and missile power
the chinese attempt to
intrude into indian territory will come
from tibet
they will have their bases there
we have our eyes on our bases on these
bases we have birds in the sky
satellites
in position we know everything that's
going on there we don't talk about it
obviously
i mean one must assume that one has
these capabilities
the chinese know that
so we know what the chinese are up to we
are keeping a very close watch on all
chinese activities north of
i mean in the tibet area
so if there is any
misadventure for the chinese in silicon
it will come from tibet
if that happens india will use air power
to defeat that you don't need to put 50
000 or 100 000 soldiers in siliguri
itself you destroy the chinese bases
using cruise missiles brahmos or using
fighter aircraft
you give them a bloody nose so that it
forces them to pull back
and we have
air power in the region you may not see
it
it may not be visible it is not designed
to be visible but it's there
we have missile power in the region once
again you're not supposed to see it
nobody is supposed to see it but it is
there
so i don't know what the media may be
saying it may be making people feel
insecure or whatever but siliguri
is not in any danger if the chinese try
anything they're gonna get more than a
bloody nose
so uh i would i would say don't be
scared rest assured india has a
situation under control
uh if the chinese try anything they will
they will learn a very bitter lesson
okay swarup vedia says what is the i2u2
group
is it a new alliance like the quad what
are its objectives
and what is india doing uh what is india
going to benefit from it
the i2 u2 group what is that
so the i2 youtube group is a coalition
or a grouping of four nations
two nations whose names start with i and
two nations whose names start with you
india
israel the uae and the usa so let's take
a look at
what the geography is like where are
these nations we know where india is i
hope you do
where is the uae it's not really far
from india here it is
dubai is part of the uae right
so it's in the persian gulf region
that's the uae
uh israel is a eastern mediterranean
nation it's over here
right
west of jordan west of saudi arabia
north of egypt
and i suppose you know where the u.s is
so it is a new coalition or a new
grouping of nations
which happened quite recently so in
you had the abraham accords between
israel and
the uae essentially and it it marked a
thawing of
an improvement of relations between
israel and these gulf countries even the
saudis now have reasonably good
relations with israel so this was done
under the presidency of mr trump right
in 2020
so as a consequence of the abraham
accord following the abraham accords
this new grouping was formed in 2021
i2u2 u2 india israel uae and the usa
now
this grouping of nations will have a
number of stated objectives in a number
of unstated objectives
i am obviously more interested in the
unstated objectives the stated
objectives are cooperation and
collaboration and things like food
security in various technologies in
trade and climate change
in fighting against pandemics like kobe
19 and obviously about exploring the
security cooperation for mutual benefit
and so on and so forth these are the
official stated objectives what are the
unstated objectives is what i would
really be interested in and obviously
unstated objectives are not stated so
one has to deduce what these objectives
are
so
when it comes to india and israel it's
very clear what our mutual
we have a very strong mutual mutually
beneficial relationship we our national
interests align there is long-term
alignment
we have common
adversaries we have common interests uh
there is a lot of positivity involved
between the two nations there is a lot
we can do to help each other
from the trade perspective from the
economic perspective from the strategic
perspective from the defense perspective
and so much cooperation and
collaboration has been happening between
india and israel
so that is a natural partnership india
israel india and uae
there is a lot of
a great amount of warmth
between india and the in the uae of late
since 2014 after mr modi came to power
so the sheikh of of the uae what's his
name i forget his name so it's an arabic
name forgive me because
because i can't remember i don't know so
uh mr modi and the leader of the uae
have a very good relationship
and india has excellent relations with
all the all these gulf countries
including saudi arabia
oman
and the uae
so oman so the uae fits into that very
nicely
no issues there so india has good
relations with israel india has good
relations with saudi arabia with the uae
and with the u.s we have
a convergence of of strategic
interests vis-a-vis china
the us obviously regards china's rise as
a big threat and obviously it is also a
big threat for india
so what are the objectives of the
i2u2
uh
so one of the objectives is energy
security from india so india india's
seeks multi-polarity in the world
the us seeks bipolarity the chinese
desire unipolarity india desires
multi-polarity so this sort of grouping
uh goes well with our envisioned idea of
multi-polarity in the world we will work
with everybody
with whom we have
shared interests
so that's what it is obviously there
will be some
strategic and geopolitical angle to it
for instance keeping china out of this
region
that could be
one of the objectives that are unstated
from the indian perspective in the u.s
perspective
the the arabs
the
emiratis etc would not really mind china
too much but they would also
prefer india because everyone knows what
china's track record is like
so that is what this thing is it is a
very new organization it may not even
have very clear updates right now but in
the long run it is good for india
because we seek good relations with all
the nations in this region with israel
with the gulf nations
and it's it's good for us so that's what
it is it's a new form it's a new
grouping
just like the quad is kind of in
informal
just like the seo shanghai cooperation
organization it has informal it's kind
of an informal thing with it i'm not
sure if it has stated objectives in the
charter but that's where we are it's a
new grouping it will take time for it to
mature and evolve and and
have clear-cut objectives that are
stated
right
okay man vashishta says what would have
happened if gamal abdul nasir had been
successful in uniting the islamic
nations of north africa and the middle
east
it is known that this was his biggest
aim to incorporate all the islamic
nations into a single islamic
superpower
power
so mr nasir ruled egypt from
1956 until 1970 when he died yeah
and yes he was a pan-africanist
pan-africanist he was a pan-arabist he
wanted a a unified arabic
power
so he
he was part of this this experiment
called the united arab republic
from 1958 to 1960 61 which was
a unified nation of egypt and syria
which is weird because they are not
quite connected take a look at the map
take a look at the map where is egypt mr
egypt is here
is all over all the way up north so
egypt and syria were part of a single
republic the united arab republic
between 1958 and 1961 i believe
right so they did
take part in this in this
experiment did not last very long
but he sought this sort of thing he
sought
he sought a pan-arab coalition and maybe
a pan-arab nation and eventually maybe a
pan-african nation
and it was nasser
who in in coordination and cooperation
with various african leaders uh created
something called the organization of
african unity
in the early 1960s it lasted until the
early 21st century i think it dissolved
in 20 2002
and gave rise to a new organization
called the african union which came into
force in 2002.
so mr nasser was kind of behind all of
this he was very much involved in this
he was also involved in the so-called
non-alignment movement which took
anybody nowhere but that's what it was
so yeah
uh
the egyptians see him as one of the one
of the major egyptian leaders they they
like him very much he's a very
well cherished and beloved leader of
egypt
mostly because of his involvement in the
1956 attempt to invade egypt and take
over suez which was done by the french
and the british
it was britain's last attempt at
regaining its its status as a world
power
they did succeed in taking over the suez
region
swa's canal region briefly before the
americans arm twisted them into giving
it up
and that's so that's what happened
so mr nazar would have been deposed had
this
this invasion been allowed to
progress to its logical conclusion but
the americans intervened which saved
nasser and out of all of this nasser
emerged as a great hero even though he
did not do much but still he emerged as
a hero and he was a very uh domineering
personality and very charismatic person
so that's why he is regarded as one of
the greatest egyptian leaders of the
past 100 or so years
and he did seek to unify the arab
nations and possibly even africa
and obviously it did not happen because
africa is still very much
colonized by the western powers
it's still very much colonized in a
variety of ways
yeah so that's what it is
so
it's impossible it would have been
impossible for him to unify africa it's
just it's just too big of a task africa
is so huge it's immense
it's an immense geography it looks kind
of small on the map because the
mercantile projection doesn't quite do
justice to the size of africa
and yet africa is is just immense
enormous it's it's very difficult to
unify
all the nations into a single
organization
and even gaddafi muammar gaddafi the
leader of libya had such uh such plans
he sought a single african currency
backed by the gold standard
and we know what happened to him so the
west will not allow this to happen they
will not allow africa to unite
right so that's
yeah didn't happen didn't work
okay let's take a couple of questions
more
dangerous thing john says what according
to you is the determining factor in
success luck or effort or both
so if you look at the most successful
people in the world
they would not have
been that successful was it not for a
certain element of luck luck is
important but you can never be lucky
unless you put in an immense amount of
hard work yeah so effort comes first if
you put in 100 of your effort
then the gods may smile upon you and
give you the two percent of luck which
will take you to the next level
so yes luck is important but luck is you
will never have luck if you just sit and
keep praying to the gods
you have to work
so effort comes first then the two
percent of luck
may come in if the gods
decide
that you are worthy of it
so 98
effort maybe one or two percent luck
that is the determining factor in
success
uh operating says i am determined to
start a podcast can you give me some
guidance regarding it and how can i
invite you
to my podcast when it expands to a
respectable size
look you want to start a podcast you
need to have a topic you need to have
some kind of plan
you can't just say i want to have a
podcast because it's great you need to
have a reason for having a podcast
you need to have a one year plan at
least as to how many episodes you want
and what are the episodes going to be
about and what is the topic going to be
about right
so that has to be there
without that your podcast won't work and
you
it has to and whatever topic you choose
has to be something that resonates with
you it's something that you should be
passionate about
right otherwise you will not be able to
sustain that over a long period of time
i believe the statistics say that most
most podcasts end after three episodes
right that sort of thing
they don't last long because people give
up it's too hard and they don't they run
out of ideas and all that
so first of all you need to determine
why you want to have a podcast is it
something that really drives you
and do you have the expertise in
whatever topic you you want to speak
about
which would allow you to sustain it for
a long period of time or maybe you want
to be an interviewer and call
interesting people
well you should ask yourself in that
case
why should interesting people come and
speak to you on your podcast there
should be something unique about you
that would
tell them that it's worth their time
so you have to think about all these
things you need to have a very clear
idea of why you're doing it you need to
have a very clear idea of what topics
you want to
make the podcast about
and you need to have a clear plan the
equipment and all that is not very
important you don't need
expensive equipment and all that you can
use reasonably inexpensive
equipment to start off with
so yeah and how can you invite me to to
your podcast well
you have to demonstrate
that that you're worth it right you need
to show that you you are serious about
what you're doing and how do you
demonstrate your series by having a
track record by having 30 40 50
if you do that if you put in the hard
work people will come
the first thing people want to see is
are you serious
i get emails every single day
i get dozens of emails every day i get
messages on instagram i get messages on
twitter i get messages on linkedin
people
requesting me to come on the podcast i
take a look at the channel it's got it's
got like one video or two videos
i have nothing against small channels
and small youtubers or small podcasters
but you have to show that you're serious
right
everybody's time is valuable is it is it
worth one hour of my time
is it going to be valuable for whatever
audience is going to watch it so you
have to make it worthwhile
so these are some of the things i could
offer to you and all the best i hope
that you
get your plan in place and i and i wish
you success
all right all the best
current says
how to overcome addiction
phone phone addiction
okay
see any addiction is it it
yeah
see
i believe addiction is something that is
a psychological reaction to
trying to try to fill some hole in your
life
and and when you don't get what you want
in your life you try to
try to fill that hole with some sort of
activity which takes the form of an
addiction some people do substance abuse
alcohol addiction or various kinds of
other substances chemicals chemical
substances drugs whatever some people
get all get addicted to social media
like you say phone or whatever it is and
so on and so forth there are all kinds
of additions that people have typically
this would be
so this means that there is something
missing in your life
and you're trying to fill that hole
by by
through this addiction so you have to go
to the root of
why you are addicted to whatever it is
that you're addicted right why are you
addicted to it and then you identify
what it is and you fill that hole with
what what really needs
what really needs to be there
and i would say that uh
to to overcome an addiction you should
replace it with something better
maybe replace it with a better addiction
maybe give up your phone addiction and
replace it with a gym addiction go to
the gym an hour every day
you know you know and and
use the time you are spending on the
phone to do that or learn some new hobby
or do some extra work or whatever it is
so at the end of the day
the only person who can help you is
yourself
and it will take willpower there is no
shortcut to these things
you have to
go through that barrier and it takes a
lot of willpower to overcome any kind of
addiction
so that is what i can say in brief i am
not an expert i'm not a counselor
but that's what that's the inside i
could offer you so all the best
andrea says what about mosquitoes even
if we are not killing by hand we use
medicines
so they die anyways so this is in
response to that uh
somebody had asked me about
should we kill ants or something like
that and i said please don't kill ants
what about mosquitoes well go ahead and
kill mosquitoes it's okay to kill
mosquitoes
there are lots of dangerous creatures in
the world sharks
tigers lions elephants crocodiles
but the animal that kills the most human
beings every year
is the mosquito
it's a it's a mosquito it's the it's a
deadly it is the most dangerous predator
that humans have and it looks so small
and harmless but it kills people through
various diseases malaria obviously they
have dengue then you have
various other
illnesses that that mosquitoes transmit
so yes go ahead kill mosquitoes you know
i always say that i am against gene
editing
and you know all genetically modified
organisms gmos etc but i would not be
opposed
to cross breeding
or would not be opposed to introducing
firefly genes into mosquitoes and making
mosquitoes glow
so even in the dark you can see the
mosquitoes flying around so you can kill
them easily so yes it's okay go ahead
kill the mosquitoes
all the best
all right we are almost at the end of
today's session
i will take a couple of questions from
the live chat if you have any
would you do you have any questions if
you have questions for me
go ahead and ask me right now i will
take a couple of questions
uh something that intrigues me please
something that's interesting
uh
something i'm not
answered before
jai shri ramji jai shri ram sanji yes
sir
mosquitos are creatures created by angra
manyu ariman where it is entirely
possible it's entirely possible that
ahriman created mosquitoes
because obviously he's the bad guy isn't
he
what about what about the shinzo abe
killing have i not answered this today
okay
um
why are there no volcanoes around india
because india does not lie in it in a
very techno tectonically
active region there are tectonically
active zones in india
but the uh
volcanoes typically exist
where the tectonic plates collide where
there are subduction zones etc the
so-called ring of fire so that's
thankfully away from india there is one
one or two volcanoes in india in the
andaman islands one is barron island
baron island and the other one is narrow
condom i believe
let me show you where it is where is
baron island it's somewhere in the
andamans
i believe it is this one is it
baron island so if you look here
you will see that there's a
volcano there it's it's it's
it's kind of dormant but sometimes it
wakes up this island
and there is another one called nara
condom or something nearby
in in this general region
so yeah so there are one or two
volcanoes two volcanoes most likely in
india and that's it and we are very
thankful that we don't have any more
because it's never fun to be near a
volcano like
like in various cities in japan
and italy and so on yeah
okay
okay i guess i guess we are done for
today
yeah we have crossed two hours
so thank you very much for all your
questions always a great pleasure
interacting with you all answering your
questions let's keep it going would you
like me to do a q a session ask a budget
session on twitter
would you like that
i could do something like that next week
perhaps as
a test as an experiment if some of you
are on twitter i could answer questions
on that so let me know in the comments
below
but until then until next time until the
next episode thank you very much take
care and i will see you soon bye